Alikhan Tortay

Location: Almaty, Kazakhstan Mobile: +77088452170 Email: tortayalikhan@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/alikhan-tortay/ github.com/alan-lq

Summary

I have experience developing social and commercial projects in React.JS and Next.JS Framework as a front-end developer in a team of 6 people. I'm mainly involved in UI-Kit development/support in companies, optimizing sites, fixing bugs, supporting new functionality.

EDUCATION

Kazakh-British Technical University

Applied Computer engineering and software

Almaty, Kazakhstan Bachelor,

September 2018 — August 2022

• Completed Relevant Courses:

Computer Science: Algorithms and Data Structures, C++, Python, Java, Computer Vision, Fullstack Dev.

EXPERIENCE

• Tengri Securities

Almaty, KZ

Software engineer, Rama Techventure

June 2023 — now

- Developed and supported two complex web applications
- Streamlined the code of a major functionality which resulted in increase of development speed

American Space & Makerspace Almaty

Almaty, KZ

Frontend internship

September 2022 — March 2023

- Gained experience with libraries and frameworks including React, React Components, and React Hooks to create dynamic and scalable user interfaces.
- Created single-page applications and used JSON APIs to exchange data between client and server.

Stack: Javascript, Json, React.js

PROJECTS

• Guardiola hub

Bot for support of traders

December 2023

- Writing unit and integration tests to improve and support the project
- Supported the front-end of the platform

Stack: React.ts, QA, Node.js, Python

• Rama August 2023

Ecosystem for IT product development

- Code refactoring
- Enhanced user interactions via fortified authentication processes: login, logout, and sign-up functionalities

Stack: React.js, TailwindCSS

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, SQL, Node.js

• Frameworks: React, Angular

- · Infrastructure: Git, Github, Gitlab
- · Others: npm, yarn, Sass/Less, Bootstrap

Courses

Full-Stack Development, American Space & MakerSpace Almaty

2022

Javascript, Udemy

2022